-怎么了　-没什么
- What? - Nothing.
别扯了　肯定有事
It's not nothing. It's always something.
爸爸没教过你怎么打绳结吗
Didn't dad teach you to tie nail knots?
他干嘛要这么做　他只打过渔人结
Why would he do that? He only ever used a fisherman's knot.
-就一个结　-不　没有
- One knot. - No, he didn't.
他至少打过三种结
No, he tied at least three.
螺旋结吗
Clinch knots?
不可能
No way.
好吧　算是我编的行了吧
Fine, I'm making it up.
爸爸都教你用干鱼饵吗
Did dad teach you mostly dry lures?
是啊　你呢
Yeah. You?
-湿的　-开玩笑吧
- Wet. - You're kidding.
但他总是这么固执
But he was always so adamant.
你也知道爸爸对钓鱼的态度
I mean, you know dad on the fishing thing.
你觉得怎样
Gee, you think?
我整个童年都在船上度过
I only spent my entire childhood with my ass in a boat.
但那个时候　都是端着鱼钩坐好
But in my day it was all about getting the hook seated.
我们是为了吃而钓鱼
We were fishing for the dinner table.
我们不是　我们总把鱼放回去
Not us. We always threw them back.
-一直是这样　-我想是他变了吧
- Always. - I guess he changed things up.
但这感觉就像是让他改变信仰之类
But that'd be like changing his religion or something.
人是会变的　我们相差12岁　这又不能怪他
People change. It's not his fault we were born 12 years apart.
的确
No.
因为自从你上了大学
No, because the minute you went off to college
就轮到我坐在船上
It was my ass in that
由他来教我用干鱼饵钓鱼了
boat and he taught me dry lures from day one.
并不是时间改变的他
This was not behavior developed over time.
你觉得他是为了我们吗
You think he did it for us?
因为他知道我们性格迥异
because he knew we were so different.
他知道你想要钓上鱼
He knew that you needed to catch the fish
而我要把鱼放回去
And I needed to throw them back.
好吧　记住他教的规则
All right, remember his rule:
在船上可不能哭
No crying in the boat.
那会吓跑了鱼
It scares the fish.
妈妈和爸爸
Mom and dad--
我是说
I mean,
也许弗罗里达的情况没这么严重
Maybe Florida wasn't hit so bad.
也许那里比较好
Maybe it's better there.
你觉得呢
Do you think?
我觉得你有鱼上钩了
I think you have a bite.
就算用的鱼饵不对
Even with the wrong knots.
天啊
Oh god.
看来不准哭的规则不管用了
So much for the no crying rule.
我想是爸爸比鱼更重要
I think that was more for dad than the fish.
《行尸走肉》
我可不会犹豫
I won't hesitate.
我不在乎枪声引来城里的行尸
I don't care if every walker in the city hears it.
你有抹布什么的么
You got a do-rag or something?
我想这锯子太钝了　锯不断手铐
I guess the saw blade was too dull for the handcuffs.
真他妈见鬼
Ain't that a bitch.
他肯定拿了东西止血　也许是他的皮带
He must have used a tourniquet-- maybe his belt.
不然不会只有这么点血迹
Be much more blood if he didn't.
莫尔　你在吗
Merle? You in here?
吉姆　你没事吧
Jim? You okay?
你再这么下去会晕过去
You keep this up, you're gonna keel over out here.
好歹喝点水吧
Drink some water at least.
他一个人摆平两只丑八怪绰绰有余
Had enough in him to take out these two sumbitchs.
只用一只手
One handed.
我哥真是我见过的最牛逼的小强
Toughest asshole I ever met, my brother.
他用起锤子能把个钉子砸烂
Feed him a hammer, he'd crap out nails.
失这么多血　是人都撑不过去
Any man can pass out from blood loss,
不管他再怎么强悍
No matter how tough he is.
宝贝儿　看看那个
Oh, baby. Will you look at that?
大家看啊
Hey, check it out.
女士们
Ladies...
多亏了你们　我的孩子晚上有的吃了
...Because of you my children will eat tonight.
-谢了　-谢戴尔吧
- Thank you. - Thank Dale.
他贡献的船和装备
It's his canoe and gear.
妈妈　看呀　这么多鱼
Mom, look. Look at all the fish.
谢了
Thank you.
可不是　你俩从哪儿学的
Yeah, whoa. Where did you two learn to do that?
-爸爸教的　-你们能教我吗
- Our dad. - Can you teach me how to do that?
当然　我会教你打绳结等等的本事
Sure. I'll teach you all about nail knots and stuff.
-如果你同意　-我可没什么意见
- If that's okay. - You won't catch me arguing.
戴尔　你多久没给卷筒加油了
Hey, Dale. When's the last time you oiled those line reels?
-都不管用了　-那个
- They are a disgrace. - I, uh,
我不想吓着大家
I don't want to alarm anyone,
但我们好像有点麻烦
But we may have a bit of a problem.
-莫尔　-这里不光只有我们
- Merle! - We're not alone here.
-记得吗　-去他妈的
- Remember? - Screw that.
他可能失血过多　你自己说的
He could be bleeding out. You said so yourself.
这被烧焦的什么玩意
What's that burned stuff?
人的皮肤
Skin.
他烧灼了残肢
He cauterized the stump.
我就说他很强悍
Told you he was tough.
没人能杀得死他
Nobody can kill Merle but Merle.
别这么想当然　他流了很多血
Don't take that on faith. He's lost a lot of blood.
是吗
Yeah?
他还不是照样从这绝境中逃了出去
Didn't stop him from busting out of this death trap.
他从这幢楼逃走了吗
He left the building?
见鬼的他干嘛这么干
Why the hell would he do that?
不然还能怎样
Why wouldn't he?
在他看来　他被丢下一个人
He's out there alone as far as he knows,
他不过是按本能行动
Doing what he's got to do.
为了活下去
Surviving.
你觉得这样能活下去
You call that surviving?
在大街上闲晃　昏过去了怎么办
Just wandering out in the streets, maybe passing out?
他在外面有出路吗
What are his odds out there?
总比被你们几个天杀的
No worse than being
铐在屋顶上烂掉来的好
handcuffed and left to rot by you sorry pricks.
你杀不了他
You couldn't kill him.
外面那些个蠢蛋活死人能杀得了他吗
Ain't so worried about some dumb dead bastard.
那1000只活死人呢
What about 1,000 dead dumb bastards?
-会怎么样　-你干嘛不去算账
- Different story? - Why don't you take a tally?
随你怎么说　我要去找他
Do what you want. I'm gonna go get him.
-达里尔　等等　-拿开你的手
- Daryl, wait. - Get your hands off me!
-你阻止不了我　-我不怪你
- You can't stop me. - I don't blame you.
他是你家人　我能理解　我也历经千辛才找到我的家人
He's family, I get that. I went through hell to find mine.
我相当理解你的感受
I know exactly how you feel.
受了这种伤　他走不了多远
He can't get far with that injury.
我们可以到附近找一找
We could help you check a few blocks around
但我们必须保持清醒
but only if we keep a level head.
这倒不难
I could do that.
得先拿到枪才行
Only if we get those guns first.
就算出于好心
I'm not strolling the streets of Atlanta
我也不在街上乱串　明白吗
with just my good intentions, okay?
吉姆
Hey, Jim.
吉姆　先停一下好吗
Jim, why don't you hold up, all right?
-跟你说几句　-干什么
- Just give me a second here, please. - What do you want?
大家都有点担心你
We're all just a little concerned, that's all.
戴尔说你挖了几个钟头了
Dale says you've been out here for hours.
-那又怎样　-你干嘛挖坑
- So? - So why are you digging?
挖地道去中国吗　吉姆
Are you heading to China, Jim?
碍你什么事　我又不伤人
What does it matter? I'm not hurting anyone.
可你这样会伤了自己
Yeah, except maybe yourself.
今天三十七度高温呢　你不能这么一直挖
It's 100 degree today. You can't keep this up.
我可以挖　挖给你看
Sure I can. Watch me.
吉姆　他们不好直说　我来说吧
Jim, they're not gonna say it so I will.
你吓到别人了
You're scaring people.
你吓到我儿子和卡萝尔的女儿
You're scaring my son and Carol's daughter.
没什么好怕的
They got nothing to be scared of.
我说你们到底怎么了
I mean, what the hell, people?
我自己要来这里　你们走开
I'm out here by myself. Why don't you all just go
让我一个人待着行吗
and leave me the hell alone?
我们觉得你该休息一下
We think that you need to take a break, okay?
去树荫下凉快一下
Why don't you go and get yourself in the shade?
吃点东西什么　说不定
Some food maybe. I'll tell you what--
过会儿我也过来
Maybe in a little bit I'll come out here
帮你一起挖
and help you myself.
吉姆　说说到底怎么了
Jim, just tell me what it's about.
去休息吧　把铲子给我
Why don't you just go ahead and give me that shovel?
-不然什么后果　-没什么后果
- Or what? - There is no or what.
我在请求你　我是来请求你
I'm asking you. I'm coming to you and I'm asking you, please.
我不想去抢你的铲子
I don't want to have to take it from you.
我要是不给呢
And if I don't, then what?
你就过来揍我
Then you're gonna beat my face in
就像揍爱德·佩尔蒂埃那样
like Ed Peletier, aren't you?
你们都瞧见他的脸了吧　被揍成啥样了都
Y'all seen his face, huh? What's left of it.
跟你过不去就是那个下场
See, now that's what happens when someone crosses you.
情况不一样　吉姆
That was different, Jim.
你又不在场　当时爱德失控了
You weren't there. Ed was out of control.
他在打他妻子
He was hurting his wife.
那是别人的家事　关他屁事
That is their marriage. That is not his.
他又不是法官　谁选你当老大了
He is not judge and jury. Who voted you king boss, huh?
吉姆　我不是来跟你吵架
Jim, I'm not here to argue with you, all right?
-把铲子给我好吗　-不行
- Just give me the shovel, okay? - No no no.
给我　吉姆
Just give me the-- Jim!
-好了安静　-你没权利
- Okay, shh shh. - You got no right!
-淡定　-你没权利
- Stop. - You got no right!
吉姆　淡定
Jim, just stop it.
-放开我　-吉姆　没人会伤害你
- Don't! - Jim. Jim, nobody's gonna hurt you.
听到吗
You hear me?
吉姆　没人会伤害你　好吗
Jim, nobody is gonna hurt you, okay?
说谎　弥天大谎
That's a lie. That's the biggest lie there is.
我对我妻子和两个儿子也这么说
I told that to my wife and my two boys.
说了几百次　不顶用
I said it 100 times. It didn't matter.
不知从哪冒出了一大堆行尸
They came out of nowhere. There were dozens of'em.
把他们从我身边拉走了
Just pulled'em right out of my hands.
我能逃走　只是因为
You know, the only reason I got away was
那些行尸只顾着吃我的家人
'cause the dead were too busy eating my family.
你不能单独行动
You're not doing this alone.
我不太爽你　连我都觉得这样不好
Even I think it's a bad idea and I don't even like you much.
这主意能行　你先听我说完
It's a good idea, okay, if you just hear me out.
如果我们一起走出去
If we go out there in a group,
会走得很慢　还引起注意
we're slow, drawing attention.
如果我单独行动　反而更加灵活
If I'm alone, I can move fast.
瞧
Look.
坦克在这　离这有五个街区
That's the tank, five blocks from where we are now.
装枪的袋子在这
That's the bag of guns.
这是第一次见面时　我拉你走进的巷子
Here's the alley I dragged you into when we first met.
-我和达里尔就去那里　-怎么是我
- That's where Daryl and I will go. - Why me?
十字弩比枪声音小些
Your crossbow is quieter than his gun.
达里尔在巷子里等着
While Daryl waits here in the alley,
我到街上去　把袋子拿来
I run up the street, grab the bag.
我们去别的地方吗
You got us elsewhere?
是的　你和T仔
You and T-dog, right.
你们到这个巷子来
You'll be in this alley here.
隔两个街区　为什么
Two blocks away? Why?
以防我不能按原路返回
I may not be able to come back the same way.
行尸可能会阻断我去路
Walkers might cut me off.
这样的话　我就不能回达里尔那儿
If that happens, I won't go back to Daryl.
只能继续往前走
I'll go forward instead,
走到你们所在的巷子
all the way around to that alley where you guys are.
不管走哪边
Whichever direction I go,
你们都能掩护我
I got you in both places to cover me.
完事之后　到这里汇合
Afterwards, we'll all meet back here.
小子　你之前是干什么的
Hey, kid, what'd you do before all this?
送比萨的　怎么了
Delivered pizzas. Why?
你个中国人胆儿挺肥啊
You got some balls for a Chinaman.
-我是韩国人　-无所谓
- I'm Korean. - Whatever.
喂　别射　你想怎样
Whoa, don't shoot me! What do you want?
我在找我哥哥　他受了重伤　你见过他吗
I'm looking for my brother. He's hurt real bad. You seen him?
- [西班牙语] 救命　-闭嘴
- Ayudame! - Shut up!
你会把僵尸都招来　快说
You're gonna bring the geeks down on us. Answer me.
-说　-救命
- Answer me. - Ayudame!
救命
Ayudame!
闭嘴　别喊了
Shut up. Shut up.
闭嘴
Shut up.
就是那个袋子　哥们
That's it. That's the bag, vato.
抢过来　抢过来
Take it! Take it!
放开我　放开我
Get off me! Get off me!
达里尔
Daryl!
回来
Come back here,
狗杂种
you son of a bitch!
快住手
Stop it.
老子他妈的要搞死你
I'm gonna kick your nuts up in your throat!
-放开我　-冷静点
- Let me go. - Chill out.
他们抓走了格伦　那个小混蛋
They took Glenn. That little bastard
还有他那帮混账同伙
and his little bastard homie friends.
老子要你屁股开花
I'm gonna stomp your ass!
伙计们　行尸把我们包围了
Guys! Guys! We're cut off!
回实验室去　快
Get to the lab. Go.
快点　见你鬼的　快走
Come on. Damn, let's go.
吉姆　喝点水吗
Jim, take some water?
-好　-喝点吗
- All right. - Yeah?
好的
All right.
给你　哥们
Here you go, bud.
能往我头上浇点吗
Pour some on my head?
好
Yeah.
这下头脑清醒点了吧
Cooling you down, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
你还得这样绑我多久
How long you gonna keep me like this?
这个嘛
Well, yeah.
等到我觉得你于人于己都不再是威胁
Until I don't think that you're a danger to yourself
到时再放了你
Or others.
如果我吓到了你们儿子和女儿　我很抱歉
Sorry if I scared your boy and your little girl.
你中暑了　没人怪你
You had sunstroke. Nobody's blaming you.
你现在不怕了吧
You're not scared now, are you?
不怕了　先生
No sir.
她说的没错　我只是被太阳晒昏了头
Your mama's right. Sun just cooked my head is all.
吉姆　知不知道你为什么挖坑
Jim, do you know why you were digging?
能说说吗
Can you say?
我有理由　就是记不得了
I had a reason. Don't remember.
我昨晚做了个梦
Something I dreamt last night.
也梦到了你爸爸　还有你
Your dad was in it. You were too.
你很为他担心　其它的就记不得了
You were worried about him. Can't remember the rest.
你是不是很担心你爸爸
You worried about your dad?
他们还没回来
They're not back yet.
我们没必要谈这个
We don't need to talk about that.
你爸爸是个警察　小子
Your dad's a police officer, son.
他乐于助人
He helps people.
没准是路上拔刀相助了一下耽搁了　没啥大不了
Probably just came across some folks needing help, that's all.
这人呐　强得很
That man, he is tough as nails.
我跟他不熟　但是…
I don't know him well but...
我看得出来
I could see it in him.
对不对
Am I right?
绝对
Oh yeah.
这世上没有任何东西能阻止他回到
There ain't nothing gonna stop him from getting back here
你还有你妈妈身边　我向你保证
To you and your mom, I promise you that.
很好
All right.
谁想来帮我清理鱼肉
Who wants to help me clean some fish, huh?
好耶　来吧　索菲亚
Sweet. Come on, Sophia.
跟紧卡萝尔　好么
Stay with Carol, all right?
你好好看着你儿子
You keep your boy close.
千万别让他离开你视线
You don't ever let him out of your sight.
那些和你一起的人　快说他们去哪了
Those men you were with, we need to know where they went.
我才不跟你说
I ain't telling you nothing.
老天　当时到底怎么回事
Jesus, man. What the hell happened back there?
我说了　这小贱人和他的傻逼哥们
I told you, this little turd and his douche bag friends
不知道从哪冒出来暴打我一顿
Came out of nowhere and jumped me.
分明是你找我的碴　妈的
You're the one who jumped me, puto,
吵着要找自己老哥
Screaming about trying
还倒过来说是我的错
to find his brother like it's my damn fault.
他们抓走了格伦　也可能抓走了莫尔
They took Glenn. Could have taken Merle too.
莫尔　这是啥鸟名字
Merle? What kind of hick name is that?
我连自己的狗也不叫莫尔
I wouldn't name my dog Merle.
-马勒隔壁　-达里尔　走开
- Damn it, - Daryl. Back off.
想知道上个惹毛我的人最后怎么了吗
Want to see what happened to the last guy that pissed me off?
这次从脚来
Start with the feet this time.
你们抓走的那个人是我们朋友
The men you were with took our friend.
我们只是想跟他们谈谈
All we want to do is talk to them,
看我们能不能协商解决
See if we can work something out.
你确定你准备好了吗
You sure you're up for this?
-好　-行
- Yeah.　- Okay.
乱动一下
One wrong move,
就让你屁股上多枝箭　自己注意点
You get an arrow in the ass. Just so you know.
阿吉会把那箭拔出来
G's gonna take that arrow out of my ass
插到你屁股上去　你也给我注意点
And shove it up yours. Just so you know.
-阿吉是谁　-吉列尔莫
- G? - Guillermo.
他是这儿的老大
He's the man here.
那好
Okay then.
让我们去会会吉列尔莫
Let's go see guillermo.
你还好吧　小兄弟
You okay, little man?
他们要剁了我的脚哇　老大
They're gonna cut off my feet, Carnal.
条子也这么狠
Cops do that?
不是他　是这个傻逼乡巴佬
Not him. This redneck puto here.
他砍下了一个人的手　还拿给我看
He cut off some dude's hand, man. He showed it to me.
-闭嘴　-就是那个男的　弟兄们
- Shut up. - Hey, that's that vato right there, homes.
他给了我屁股一箭　想怎样
He shot me in the ass with an arrow. What's up, homes, huh?
冷静　淡定　都冷静
Chill, ease, chill. Chill.
真有这事
This true?
他要剁了小米盖尔的脚
He wants Miguelito's feet?
真变态　哥们
That's pretty sick, man.
我们是想来和平地谈谈
We were hoping more for a calm discussion.
那乡巴佬欺负了菲利普的小表弟
That hillbilly jumps Felipe's little cousin,
打了他　还威胁要剁了他脚
Beats on him, threatens to cut off his feet,
菲利普屁股上还中了一箭
Felipe gets an arrow in the ass
你还来搞和平谈判
And you want a calm discussion?
你真搞笑
You fascinate me.
当时局势紧张
Heat of the moment.
双方都有做错的地方
Mistakes were made on both sides.
那人到底是你的谁　你俩看着不像是亲戚
Who's that dude to you anyway? You don't look related.
不管怎么说　他是我们自己人
He's one of our group, more or less.
我肯定你有一些像他那样的人
I'm sure you have a few like him.
我哥哥也在里面么
You got my brother in there?
不好意思　我们这白人卖完了
Sorry, we're fresh out of white boys.
不过亚洲人我还有　有兴趣么
But I've got asian. You interested?
我有一个你们的人　你有一个我们的人
I have one of yours, you have one of mine.
公平交易吧
Sounds like an even trade.
-我怎么没觉得　-阿吉
- Don't sound even to me. - G.
-不是吧　-我的人被打了
- Come on, man. - My people got attacked.
他们的汤药费我找谁要去
Where's the compensation for their pain and suffering?
最关键的是　我那袋枪呢
More to the point, where's my bag of guns?
-枪　-小米盖尔在街上看见的那袋子
- Guns? - The bag Miguel saw in the street.
菲利普和约格打算回去拿的那个
The bag Felipe and Jorge were going back to get.
-那袋枪　-你弄错了
- That bag of guns. - You're mistaken.
-怎么错了　-你说是你的
- I don't think so. - About it being yours.
那可是我的枪
It's my bag of guns.
那袋子就在大街上
The bag was in the street.
谁看见了都能说是自己的
Anybody could come around and say it was theirs.
我难道听你说啥就是啥
I'm supposed to take your word?
何不让我的人放下对着你们脑门的枪
What's to stop my people from unloading on you
然后让我拿走本就是我的东西
right here and now and I take what's mine?
你大可以这么做
You could do that.
也未必
Or not.
得了　快点交易啊
Come on, man. Make the trade.
拜托了
Please.
喂喂
Oye.
二选一
I see two options.
你带着小米盖尔和那袋枪回来
You come back with Miguel and my bag of guns,
大家都没事
Everybody walks.
要么你们全副武装过来
Or you come back locked and loaded,
来个一决雌雄看看谁比谁狠
We'll see which side spills more blood.
枪可比金子还管用
Them guns are worth more than gold.
金子保不了你全家小命或是给你吃的
Gold won't protect your family or put food on the table.
你要为那小子放弃这些吗
You're gonna give that up for that kid?
如果这能换回格伦　我是赞成
If I knew we'd get Glenn back, I might agree.
但你觉得那哥们会守信用吗
But you think that vato across the way is just gonna hand him over?
-你们说阿吉是骗子吗　-关你屁事
- You calling G a liar?　- Are you a part of this?
你想挨揍吗
You want to hold onto your teeth?
问题是　你信那家伙吗
Question is, do you trust that man's word?
不　问题在于你愿意拿啥去赌
No, question is what are you willing to bet on it?
可能不止那些枪　还要搭上你的命
Could be more than them guns. Could be your life.
格伦值得你这么做吗
Glenn worth that to you?
我欠他一条命
What life I have I owe to him.
格伦之前根本不认识我
I was nobody to Glenn,
我只是个困在坦克里的白痴
just some idiot stuck in a tank.
他完全可以撒手不管　但他没有
He could have walked away, but he didn't.
我也不会丢下他
Neither will I.
那你想把枪交出去吗
So you're gonna hand the guns over?
我可没说
I didn't say that.
这里没你们的事了
There's nothing keeping you two here.
你们走吧　回营地去
You should get out, head back to camp.
要我们怎么跟你家人交代
And tell your family what?
拜托　你们简直疯了
Come on, this is nuts.
照阿吉说的去做
Just do like G says.
枪我是看到了　但没有都放在包里
I see my guns but they're not all in the bag.
因为这不是你的枪
That's because they're not yours.
我说过吧
I thought I mentioned that.
我们干嘛不一枪毙了这些傻子
Let's just shoot these fools right now, ese. All right?
打个他们屁股开花
Unload on their asses, ese.
我看你们还没搞清事情的严重性
I don't think you fully appreciate the gravity of the situation.
清楚得很
No, I'm pretty clear.
你的人还你了　我要我的人
You have your man. I want mine.
我要把那小子切片　用来喂狗
I'm gonna chop up your boy. I'm gonna feed him to my dogs.
那可是你见过的最凶狠的食人动物
They're the evilest, nastiest man-eating bitches you ever saw.
一次大甩卖时我从恶魔手里买的
I picked them up from Satan at a yard sale.
我警告过你　你他妈是聋子吗
I told you how it has to be. Are you woefully deaf?
不　我听力好得很　你说全副武装地回来
No, my hearing's fine. You said come locked and loaded.
如你所愿　我们来了
Okay then, we're here.
菲利普　菲利普
Felipe! Felipe!
奶奶　快回去和其他人待在一起
Abuela, go back with the others-- now.
快让那老太婆离开这
Get that old lady out of the line of fire!
奶奶　听话　好吗
Abuela, listen to your mijo, okay?
你不应该来在这儿
This is the not the place for you right now.
吉伯特先生呼吸困难
Mr. Gilbert is having trouble breathing.
他要哮喘药
He needs his asthma stuff.
小卡尔找不到
Carlito didn't find it.
他需要吃药
He needs his medicine.
菲利普　去把这事解决了
Felipe, go take care of it, okay?
看好你奶奶
And take your grandmother with you.
他们是什么人
Who are those men?
别把他带走
Don't you take him.
-老奶奶　-菲利普是个好孩子
- Ma'am? - Felipe's a good boy.
他有他的缺点　但他已经很努力了
He have his trouble but he pull himself together.
我们需要他
We need him here.
老奶奶
Ma'am,
我不是来逮捕他的
I'm not here to arrest your grandson.
那你们找他干什么
Then what do you want him for?
他在
He's...
帮我们找一个失踪的人
helping us find a missing person.
一个叫格伦的小伙子
Fella named Glenn.
那个亚裔小伙子吗
The Asian boy?
他和吉伯特先生在一起
He's with Mr. Gilbert.
来　我带你去见他
Come. Come, I show you.
他需要吃药
He needs his medicine.
让他们过去
Let 'em pass.
奶奶　来吧　带我去他那儿
Abuela, por favor. Take me to him.
好了
All right.
很简单　呼吸
Nice and easy. Just breathe.
呼吸　把气呼出来　呼吸
Just breathe. Just let it out. Just breathe.
放松
Just relax.
-这到底是怎么回事　-哮喘病
- What the hell is this?　- An asthma attack.
会突然呼吸困难
Couldn't get his breath all of a sudden.
我还以为你被拿去喂狗了
I thought you were being eaten by dogs, man.
能跟你说几句吗
Could I have a word with you?
你是我见过的最蠢的混蛋
You're the dumbest son of a bitch I ever met.
我们来是准备杀光你们所有人
We walked in there ready to kill every last one of you.
很高兴你没那么做
Well, I'm glad it didn't go down that way.
如果真的那样　我要沾上怎样的血债啊
If it had, that blood would be on my hands.
我不也是吗　我们会还击
Mine too. We'd have fought back.
这也不是第一次了
Wouldn't be the first time we've had to.
保护食物　药物　还有这里的一切
Protect the food, the medicine-- what's left of it.
这些人　这些老人
These people, the old ones--
这的员工自己跑了　就把他们扔下等死
The staff took off, just left 'em here to die.
只有我和菲利普留下了
Me and Felipe were the only ones who stayed.
你们是什么人　医生吗
What are you, doctors?
菲利普是名护士　特别护理人员
Felipe's a nurse-- a special care provider.
我呢
Me,
我是一名保安
I'm the custodian.
其他人呢
What about the rest of your crew?
这些人都是来探望父母或祖父母
The vatos trickle in to check on their parents, their grandparents.
他们看到这状况　大多都决定留下来
They see how things are and most decide to stay.
这样也好　我们需要帮手
It's a good thing too. We need the muscle.
灾难降临后　我们所遇到的人里
The people we've encountered since things fell apart,
最糟糕的就是掠夺者
The worst kind-- plunderers,
用武力抢夺资源
The kind that take by force.
-我们不是　-我怎么知道
- That's not who we are.　- How was I to know?
我的人受到攻击　你还挟持了米盖尔
My people got attacked and you show up with Miguel hostage--
很明显嘛
Appearances.
世道变了
Guess the world changed.
没变
No.
还是和以前一样　弱肉强食
It's the same as it ever was. The weak get taken.
在这里我们尽己所能
So we do what we can here.
我们本来想弄几辆车
The vatos work on those cars,
商量着把这些老人送出城
talk about getting the old people out of the city.
但大部分人连自己上厕所都难
But most can't even get to the bathroom by themselves,
所以这只是纸上谈兵
so that is a dream
但大伙还是很忙
Still, it keeps the crew busy,
至少这里有值得做的事
and that's worth something.
我们把窗户都封起来
So we barred all the windows,
只留了一个出口　其他都焊死了
Welded all the doors shut except for one entrance.
那些哥们　他们到外面去
The vatos, they go out,
搜寻一些能维持生活的东西
scavenge what they can to keep us going.
我们日夜监视着周边　一边等待
We watch the perimeter night and day and we wait.
这里的人
The people here,
他们都指望我了
They all look to me now.
不知道为什么
I don't even know why.
因为你靠得住
Because they can.
好吧　回亚特兰大一趟只捡回顶帽子
Admit it, you only came back to Atlanta for the hat.
别告诉别人
Don't tell anybody.
你把一半的枪支弹药都给他们了
You've given away half our guns and ammo.
-不到一半　-为了什么
- Not nearly half.　- For what?
一群随时会进棺材的死老家伙们吗
Bunch of old farts who are gonna die off momentarily anyhow?
说真的　你认为他们还能撑多久
Seriously, how long you think they got?
我们自己又能熬多久
How long do any of us?
-我的神啊　-咱们的货车死哪去了
- Oh my god. - Where the hell's our van?
-车就停在这　谁会开走　-莫尔
- We left it right there. Who would take it? - Merle.
他肯定回营地报仇了
He's gonna be taking some vengeance back to camp.
包装纸　彩色纸巾都没有吗
Wrapping paper, color tissue, anything?
有没有搞错
Seriously?
你怎么连这些都没有
How can you not have any?
要是有人提前通知会有大灾难的话
Had I been informed of the impending apocalypse
我会备些存活
I'd have stocked up.
明天是艾米的生日
It's Amy's birthday tomorrow.
我总会在日历上标记重要日子以免记错
I've been marking days on the calendar just to make sure.
礼物不包装可不行
You don't give a gift unwrapped.
别急
Deep breath.
应该能找到用得上的东西
I'm sure I'll find something here.
我把石头堆成了一圈
I, uh, built up the rocks all around.
看见没　这样火苗就能烧得高一些
See? So the flames can be a little higher
而不用担心被发现
and have 'em be hidden.
吉姆　现在感觉怎么样
Hey, Jim. How you feeling, man?
好些了　恢复得差不多了
I'm better. More myself now.
希望你能理解我这么做的理由…
I hope you understand the need for this--
让你消停一会
This timeout.
我必须考虑到其他人
I've got others I've got to think about.
我只是想确保你不会有…
I just want to make sure there's no--
有什么怨恨情绪
There's no hard feelings.
没有　我完全理解
There's not. I do understand.
那就好
Okay.
过来加入大伙的行列吧
Why don't you come join in with the rest of us?
油炸超级大鱼呢
Big ol' fish fry.
-我很乐意　-好
- I'd like that very much. - Okay.
出来跟大伙待在一起吧
Why don't you come outside with everybody?
那些人都给我去死吧
Hell with them people.
他们头上要是着火了　休想我撒尿灭火
Wouldn't piss on them if their heads were on fire.
站住
Hey!
你给我留在这
Why don't you stay here?
陪着你老爸我
Keep your daddy company.
爱德　她想跟大伙待在一起
Ed, she wants to join in.
-走吧　-真有种
- Come on. - Fine.
都给我滚
Hell with the both of you.
这倒好　耳根清净　我可以睡个好觉
Ain't no need to be bothering me no more the rest of the night.
请把鱼递过来一下
Pass the fish, please.
-接着　-哇噢　人间美味啊
- Here you go. - Man o man, that's good.
真怀念这味
I miss this.
我得问你个事　我憋得实在是辛苦
I've got to ask you, man. It's been driving me crazy.
-啥事　-那块表
- What? - That watch.
我这表有啥问题吗
What's wrong with my watch?
我每天都看你给这玩意上发条
I see you every day, the same time, winding that thing
就跟山村牧师作弥撒一样坚持不懈
like a village priest saying mass.
这事我私底下也寻思过
I've wondered this myself.
这事有啥好奇怪的
I'm missing the point.
如果我没弄错的话
Unless I've misread the signs,
世界末日貌似已经来临了
the world seems to have come to an end.
至少这世界已经处于濒临状态很久了
At least hit a speed bump for a good long while.
但你还每天给那破表上发条
But there's you every day winding that stupid watch.
看时间啊　通晓事态很重要不是吗
Time-- it's important to keep track, isn't it?
至少得知道日期吧
The days at least.
你不觉得吗　安德莉亚
Don't you think, Andrea?
挺我一下吧
Back me up here.
我很喜欢…　很喜欢
I like-- I like what, um,
一位父亲把传家手表传给儿子时
a father said to son when he gave him a watch
所说的一些话
that had been handed down through generations.
他说
He said,
这块表是一切希望
"I give you the mausoleum
和欲望的陵墓
of all hope and desire,
它会满足你的个人需求
which will fit your individual needs
就同它曾经满足我和我父亲的需求一样
no better than it did mine or my father's before me;
我把表给你
I give it to you
不是要你记住时间
not that you may remember time,
而是让你可以忘掉时间
but that you may forget it for a moment
偶尔忘掉一次
now and then
而不是费尽心机　想对抗时间流逝
and not spend all of your breath trying to conquer it."
你太非主流了
You are so weird.
这话可不是我说的　是福克纳(《喧哗与骚动》的作者)
It's not me. It's Faulkner.
威廉·福克纳　或许是我意译得不好吧
William Faulkner. Maybe my bad paraphrasing.
-你去哪　-我得去尿尿
- Where are you going? - I have to pee.
老天　你也太一惊一乍了吧
Jeez, you try to be discreet around here--
我他妈的不是让你们别来吵我吗
Thought I told y'all to leave me the hell alone, didn't I?
搞什么
Hey!
忘记我说什么了吗
What'd I say?
厕纸用光了吗
We're out of toilet paper?
-妈妈　-卡尔
- Mom! - Carl!
洛莉　拉他趴下
Lori, get him down!
我的天呐
Oh my god.
快　快点
Go! Go!
我就在这　肖恩　我们该怎么办
I'm right here. Shane, what do we do?
-肖恩　-跟我来
- Shane? - Follow me!
不　不
No! No!
天呐　我的天呐
Oh god! Oh my god!
救救我
Help me.
天呐　我不知道该怎么办
Oh god, I don't know what to do.
我不知道该做什么
I don't know what to do.
-过来　跟着　跟紧　-卡萝尔
- Come on. Come on, stay close. - Carol!
跟紧
Stay close!
大家快点　快到这边来
Come on, y'all! Work your way up here!
正前方有一个　肖恩
Right in front of you. Shane!
快到房车上去　快
Get to the R.V.! Go!
-肖恩　肖恩　-跟着我
- Shane! Shane! - Stay with me.
跟在我后面　莫拉莱斯　到这边来
Stay behind me. Morales, work up here!
-到我后面来　快点　-咱们走
- Get behind me! Come on! - Let's go!
跟着我
Stay with me.
快点　快到温尼巴格车这边来
Come on, make your way to the Winnebago!
宝贝　卡尔
Baby! Carl!
宝贝
Baby!
-爸爸　-卡尔
- Dad! - Carl!
艾米
Amy.
我不知道该怎么办　艾米
I don't know what to do, Amy.
艾米
Oh, Amy.
不
Oh no no.
艾米
Amy!
我现在想起我做过的梦了
I remember my dream now,
为什么我要挖这些坑
Why I dug the holes.